(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 1,
"subtitles": 2
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
残響散歌
Zankyou Sanka
作詞：aimerrhythm 作曲：飛内将大
Lyrics: aimerrhythm  Composition: Masahiro Tobinai
誰が袖に咲く花か
Whose flower blooms on whose sleeve?
ただそこに藍を落とした
Simply dropping indigo there.
派手に色を溶かす夜に
In the night that gaudily melts colors,
銀朱の月を添えて
Adorn it with a vermilion moon.
転がるように風を切って
Cutting through the wind as if rolling,
躓くごとに強くなった
I grew stronger every time I stumbled.
光も痛みも怒りも
The light, the pain, and the anger—
全部抱きしめて
I'll embrace it all.
選ばれなければ
If you aren't the chosen one,
選べばいい
Just choose for yourself.
声を轟かせて
Let your voice roar,
夜のその向こうへ
To the other side of the night.
涙で滲んでた
Echo all the way,
あんなに遠くの景色まで 響き渡れ
To that distant scenery blurred by tears.
何を奏でて？
What are you playing?
誰に届けたくて？
Who do you want to reach?
不確かなままでいい
It's fine to remain uncertain.
どんなに暗い感情も
No matter how dark the emotions,
どんなに長い葛藤も
No matter how long the conflict,
歌と散れ 残響
Scatter with the song, resonance.
誰が一人迷い夜
Who is lost alone in the night?
紅い熱帯夜を剥けば
If you peel back the red tropical night,
派手な色も摩訶不思議に
Even gaudy colors become mysterious.
真紅の過去冴え渡れ
Let the crimson past shine clear.
この先どんな辛い時も
No matter how hard the times ahead,
口先よりも胸を張って
Stand with pride rather than just words.
描いた夢の灯りを
All the lights of the dreams I drew,
全部辿るだけ
I'll just follow them all.
逃げ出すため
You didn't come all this way
ここまで来たんじゃないだろ？
Just to run away, did you?
(Vocalizing)
声を枯らして燃える花のように
Singing until my voice is gone like a burning flower
闇間を照らしたら
Lighting up the darkness
曖昧過ぎる世界も不鮮明にして
Blurring even this overly ambiguous world
夜を数えて朝を描くような
Counting the nights and drawing the morning
鮮やかな音を鳴らす
Letting out a vivid sound
どんなに深い後悔も
No matter how deep the regret
どんなに高い限界も
No matter how high the limit
かき消して
Drown it all out
残響だだだだ...
Echoing da da da da...
はい！ということで、ホロアコースティックライブ in Summer、始まりましたー！
Alright! And so, holoAcousticLive in Summer has begun!
イェーイ！
Yay!
始まったよー！
It's started!
It's begun!
はい、ということでお越しくださっている皆様、ありがとうございます！
Yes! Thank you so much to everyone who's here today!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
それでは最初に、今日はね、いろんな一緒に歌っていただくメンバーがいっぱいいるんですけども
First of all, we have many members joining us to sing today,
自己紹介をそれぞれさせていただきたいと思います！
but we'd like to start with our self-introductions!
まずわ、ホロライブ6期生、秘密結社holoXの...
First, Hololive 6th Gen, from the Secret Society holoX...
頭脳！博衣こよりだよ！よろしくお願いします！
The Brain! It's Hakui Koyori! Nice to meet you!
イェーイ！よろしくー！
Yay! Nice to meet you!
はい、そして1曲目から来ていただいたのは、まずミオ先輩！
Alright, and joining us from the first song, first up is Mio-senpai!
うち、うち、うちだよ！大神ミオだよ！
Uchi, uchi, it's uchi! It's Ookami Mio!
ホロライブゲーマーズの大神ミオです！よろしくどうぞー！
I'm Ookami Mio from Hololive Gamers! Pleased to meet you!
イェーイ！よろしくー！
Yay! Nice to meet you!
そして...
And...
私、わぁ！ちょっと待って！ちゃんと自己紹介しないと！
Me—whoa! Wait a sec! I have to introduce myself properly!
みなさーん！森カリオペです！ホロライブEnglishの...
Everyone! I'm Mori Calliope! From Hololive English...
死神です！です！よろしくお願いします！楽しもう！
I'm the Reaper! Death! Nice to meet you! Let's have fun!
Let's have fun everyone!
イェーイ！
Yay!
はい、お忙しい中、こうしてライブ出演していただきありがとうございます！
Yes, thank you so much for joining this live despite your busy schedules!
いえいえ、こちらこそ！呼んでいただいてありがとうございます！
No, thank you! Thanks for having us!
はい、そしてですね、今回はなんとピアノも生演奏でお届けさせていただきます！
Yes, and this time, we're bringing you live piano accompaniment too!
はい、こよりの生誕ライブでも演奏していただきました、
He also played at my birthday live—
ウイングさんです！
It's Wing-san!
わぁ、素敵です！美しい！
Wow, how wonderful! Beautiful!
はい、ということで、このライブはですね、最初から最後まで...
Right, so this live performance, from start to finish...
完全生放送、そして生演奏でお届けさせていただきますので、
Will be a completely live broadcast with live music,
よしなに、よろしくお願いいたします！
So please, enjoy the show!
ま、なんでこのライブを演ることになったかと言いますとですね、
As for why we decided to hold this live show,
普通のライブ、生誕ライブとか周年ライブって、ダンスレッスン頑張ったりとか、
For regular lives, like birthday or anniversary shows, we work hard on dance lessons,
ゲストパートは収録でやったりとか、
Do pre-recordings for guest parts,
後ろのモニター作ったりとか、とにかく準備が大変なんですよね。
Create visuals for the background monitors—the prep is just a lot of work.
めちゃくちゃ大変だよね。いっぱい演ることあって。
It really is tough. There's so much to do.
一つ作るのにすごく時間がかかるんですけど、
It takes so much time to put one together.
アコースティックライブだったら、集まって、演奏していただいて、
But for an acoustic live, we could just gather, have someone play,
歌ったら、当日でいけるんじゃね？っていうのを、
And sing—and we thought, couldn't we just do it on the day?
ちょっとチャレンジしてみたという形になっております！
So this is us taking on that challenge!
素敵なチャレンジ！
What a wonderful challenge!
歌、歌っていただくので、皆様には大変なんですけど、
It's tough for everyone because you're singing live,
でも今日楽しかったよね！本当に楽しかった！
But it's been fun today, hasn't it? It really was fun!
ミオちゃんと、お揃いみたいな感じだね！
We kind of match with Mio-chan!
そうそう！でも、真ん中にこよりが入ることでなんかいい感じにまとまってるね！
Right! But with Koyori in the middle, it balances out nicely!
このカラーリング的に、この並びになりました！
We ended up in this order because of the coloring!
もしかしたら今ね、ちょっと、あの、コメントが止まっちゃってるかもしれないんですけども、
The comments might have stopped for a bit right now,
コメントが壊れちゃったかも、壊れちゃってるかもしれないんですけど、
They might be broken, or at least they seem that way,
また動き出すと思うので、皆さんちょっと様子見つつ...
But I think they'll start moving again, so please bear with us...
あとトレンド今3位だそうです！ありがとうございます！
And apparently, we're trending #3 right now! Thank you!
序盤なのにもうトレンド3位！早ーい！
Trending #3 already and we just started! So fast!
はい、そんな感じで、ハッシュタグはこちら「#holoAcousticLive」。
Yes, and the hashtag is right here: #holoAcousticLive.
使ってください！お願いします！
Please use it! We'd appreciate it!
スクショも感想も全部見ますので、ぜひツイートしてください！
I'll be checking all your screenshots and thoughts, so please tweet them!
よろしくお願いします！
Thank you!
さて、1曲目は残響散歌でしたけれども、ミオ先輩どうでしたか？
So, the first song was 'Zankyosanka'. Mio-senpai, how was it?
はい！えーっと、すごいい、あの、こうしてなんてんだろうね...
Yes! Well, it was really... how should I put it...
一緒に歌うのめっちゃ楽しいよね！
It's so much fun to sing together like this!
楽しい！歌に集中できますからね、このアコースティックだと。
It is! You can really focus on the singing with an acoustic set.
かっこいい感じの歌をこうやって歌うの、すごい楽しかったな、って。
It was really fun to sing such a cool song this way.
...お餅も大好きだし。
...and I love mochi too.
わかるー。
I know, right?
こよりも最近、歌めっちゃ頑張ってて、すごいうまくなったからさ。
Koyori's been working so hard on her singing lately, and she's gotten really good.
うれしいー！うれしいけど、緊張しちゃった！1曲目だけど...
I'm so happy! Happy, but I was nervous! Even though it's just the first song...
ちょっと一緒に歌えて、すごいテンション上がりました！ありがとうございました！
Singing together really got my energy up! Thank you so much!
ありがとうございましたー！
Thank you very much!
カリ先輩、どうですか？
Calli-senpai, what did you think?
おお、かっこいい曲大好きで！イェーイ！
Oh, I love cool songs! Yay!
実は、あの、この曲あんまり知らなかったから...
To be honest, um, I didn't know this song very well...
練習してくれた。知ってたけど、あの、歌ったことなかったから...
She practiced it for us. I knew of it, but I'd never sung it before...
何回も練習して...
I practiced it over and over...
少しずつうまくなってきたかもしれないけど、頑張りました！
I think I might've gotten a bit better, but I did my best!
素晴らしい！
Wonderful!
もう元々知ってると勝手に思うぐらい上手だったよね！
You were so good I would've thought you knew it all along!
完璧でした！ありがとう！
It was perfect! Thank you!
かっこいい曲で...
With such a cool song...
こちらこそ。Nice choice!
Likewise. Nice choice!
コメント生き返ってる？
Is the chat coming back to life?
あ、生き返った！よかった、よかった！
Oh, it's alive! Good, good!
見てる見てる。
They're watching, they're watching.
ということでね、こより的には、ちょっと、あの、今日は...
So, for me, um, today...
夏っぽい曲を揃えて、インサマーな感じでやりたいなと...
I wanted to pick some summery songs for an "in summer" feel...
思って選曲してたんですけども。
...that's how I chose the setlist.
結構ね、夏の曲ってエモい曲が多くて。
A lot of summer songs are quite emotional.
しっとりね。
Mellow ones, right?
そう。でも1発目はやっぱかっこよくバーンって盛り上げて始めたいなと...
Yeah. But for the first one, I wanted to start with a cool, high-energy bang...
思ったので、これを選びまして。
...so that's why I chose this one.
かっこいい2人に挟まれて、大丈夫かなー？みたいな感じだったんですけど...
I was a bit worried being sandwiched between two cool people, but...
一緒に歌えて、めちゃくちゃ楽しかった！
...singing together was so much fun!
かっこよかった！よかった、ありがとうございました！
It was so cool! I'm glad, thank you very much!
はい、ということで、それではそろそろ次の曲に行くメンバーを...
Alright then, it's about time to call out the members...
お呼びしたいと思いますよ！
...for the next song!
ビジュー！
Bijou!
Hey!
わー！わー！Biboo! かわいいねー！
Whoa! Whoa! Biboo! You're so cute!
Hi! では Introduce, OK?
Hi! Now, time for an introduction, OK?
えっと、ボンビジュー！ホロライブEnglish -Advent- の輝く宝石...
Um, Bon-Bijou! The shining gemstone of Hololive English -Advent-...
古石ビジュだよ！キラキラ〜、古石〜！
...Koseki Bijou! Sparkle sparkle, Koseki!
わー！キラキラ〜！
Whoa! Sparkle sparkle!
Thank you for coming today!
ちっちゃい！かわいい！
So tiny! So cute!
みんな、みんな、すごいちっちゃいよ！
Everyone, look, she's so tiny!
ちっちゃい！かわいい！
Tiny! Cute!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
Cute. ね、このあとビジュ、Singing, どう？緊張してる？
Cute. So, Bijou, how are you feeling about the singing? Nervous?
ちょっと緊張...
A little nervous...
ちょっと緊張？かわいい！
A little nervous? How cute!
はい、ではこのあとはですね、2曲続けてお届けさせていただくんですけども...
Alright, next up we'll be performing two songs in a row...
次の曲はカリ先輩とビジュの2人で！
...the next song will be a duet by Calli-senpai and Bijou!
Oh my god! Yeah! Represent! Represent!
ぺぺぺぺーん！
Pe-pe-pe-peen!
エモくない感じなのかな？あの、なんかちょっとヒップホップなのかな？
Is it going to be non-emotional? Like, maybe a bit hip-hop?
どうなのかな？ Rock? Oh yeah! Rock!
I wonder. Rock? Oh yeah! Rock!
さあ、どんな曲なのか...
Now, what kind of song could it be...
Rock 'n' roll! Rock 'n' roll! Rock 'n' rollかもしれない。
Rock 'n' roll! Rock 'n' roll! It might be rock 'n' roll.
増えるかも？かもしれない。
Maybe more will join? Maybe.
でも2人のね、声にめちゃくちゃ合う曲を選んでますので、堪能していただきたい。
But we've picked a song that fits their voices perfectly, so please enjoy it.
今回選曲したんだよね、今回ね。
You chose the songs this time, didn't you?
そうですね、セトリは決めさせていただきました。
That's right, I was given the chance to decide the setlist.
ありがとう！はい。堪能していただけると嬉しいなと思います。
Thank you! Yes. I hope you'll all enjoy it.
では我々は一緒にちょっと客席行きましょう！
Now, let's head over to the audience seats together!
OKです！ゆっくり休んでください！
OK! Please take a good rest!
頑張ってね、2人とも！見てるよ！See you!
Good luck, you two! We'll be watching! See you!
わっせ、わっせ、わっせ... Just you and me now!
Hup, hup, hup... Just you and me now!
I guess it's just us now! Yeah, yeah, yeah!
English time, English time! 大丈夫ですか？
English time, English time! Are you alright?
大丈夫ですか？英語、英語話せるかな？
Are you alright? I wonder if I can speak English...
まあ、話せなくてもいいよ。楽しもう！
Well, it's fine if you can't. Let's just have fun!
Let's sing a song! Yeah! うん、OK! Rock!
Let's sing a song! Yeah! Yeah, OK! Rock!
And roll! Rock and roll! Rock, roll!
OK! We're rock 'n' rolling!
And now, please listen everyone to... 風といっしょに。
And now, please listen everyone to... Together with the Wind.
風といっしょに / 作詞：戸田昭吾 作曲：たなかひろかず
Together with the Wind / Lyrics: Shogo Toda, Composition: Hirokazu Tanaka
歩きつづけて どこまで ゆくの
I keep on walking, how far will I go?
かぜに たずねられて 立ちどまる
Asked by the wind, I come to a halt
しずかな 鼓動 ドクンとならして
A quiet heartbeat, thumping out a rhythm
たった ひとり...
All alone...
...歩きつづけるの
...walking on.
命始まった やがて
Life began, and then...
何かを求めて 小さな手のひらを広げ
...seeking something, you spread your small palms.
君はすぐに見つけたね 君じゃない誰かを
You found it right away, someone other than yourself.
誕生を祝う どよめく笛の音
Celebrating birth, the stirring sound of flutes.
いくつも過ぎたけど
Many have passed,
ただ一つを ふるさと旅立った
...left their hometown for just one thing.
今も何かを求めて
Still seeking something even now...
大きな瞳 輝いて
...with large, shining eyes.
君のポケットの中には
Inside your pocket...
君じゃない誰かとの
...with someone other than yourself...
いくつもの出会い
...many encounters...
いくつもの別れ
...many partings.
幻のような 思い出も
Even memories like illusions...
愛おしい
...are precious.
歩きつづけて
Keep on walking...
どこまで行くの
...how far will you go?
風にたずねられて
Asked by the wind...
空を見る
...I look at the sky.
歩きつづけて
Keep on walking...
どこまで行こうか
...how far shall we go?
風といっしょに また
Together with the wind, once again...
歩きだそう
...let's start walking.
大地踏みしめ
Stepping firmly on the earth...
どこまでも行こう
...let's go everywhere.
目指した あの夢を
Until that dream we aimed for...
つかむまで
...is within our grasp.
大地踏みしめ
Stepping firmly on the earth...
どこまでも行こう
...let's go everywhere.
目指した あの夢を
Until that dream we aimed for...
つかむまで
...is within our grasp.
ラララ...
La la la...
もう忘れてしまったかな
Have you forgotten by now?
夏の木陰に座ったまま
As we sat in the shade of a summer tree.
アイスを口に放り込んで 風を待っていた
Popping ice into our mouths, waiting for the wind.
もう忘れてしまったかな
Have you forgotten by now?
世の中の全部嘘だらけ
Everything in this world is full of lies.
本当の価値を二人で 探しに行こうと笑ったこと
The time we laughed about going together to find the true value.
忘れないように
So as not to forget...
色褪せないように
...so as not to fade.
形に残るものが 全てじゃないように
So that things that remain in form are not everything.
言葉をもっと教えて
Tell me more words.
夏が来るって教えて
Tell me that summer is coming.
僕は描いてる
I'm drawing...
風にスカートが揺れて
My skirt sways in the wind
思い出なんて忘れて
Forgetting all about my memories
浅い呼吸をする
I take a shallow breath
汗を拭って夏めく
Wiping away sweat, summer begins
もう忘れてしまったかな
I wonder if you've forgotten already
夏の木陰に座った頃を
The time when we sat in the summer shade
遠くの丘から顔を出した
There was a cloud peeking out
雲があったじゃないか
From the distant hill, remember?
君はそれを掴もうとして
You tried to reach out and grab it
馬鹿みたいに空を切った手で
With your hand cutting the air like a fool
僕は紙に雲一つ書いて
I drew a single cloud on a piece of paper
笑って握ってみせて
And showed you as I gripped it with a smile
忘れないように
So that I won't forget
色褪せないように
So that it won't fade away
歴史に残るものが全てじゃないから
Because things that remain in history aren't everything
今だけはもう忘れて
Just for now, forget it all
言葉を全部忘れて
Forget every single word
君は笑ってる
You're laughing
夏を待っている僕ら亡霊だ
We're ghosts waiting for the summer
心をもっと教えて
Tell me more about your heart
夏の匂いを教えて
Tell me about the scent of summer
浅い呼吸をする
I take a shallow breath
忘れないように
So that I won't forget
色褪せないように
So that it won't fade away
心に響くものが全てじゃないから
Because things that resonate in the heart aren't everything
言葉をもっと教えて
Tell me more words
さよならだって教えて
Even teach me how to say goodbye
今も見るんだよ
I still see it even now
夏に咲いてる花に亡霊を
A ghost in the flowers blooming in summer
言葉じゃなくて時間を
Not words, but time
時間じゃなくて心を
Not time, but the heart
浅い呼吸をする
I take a shallow breath
汗を拭って夏めく
Wiping away sweat, summer begins
夏の匂いがする
It smells like summer
もう忘れてしまったかな
I wonder if you've forgotten already
夏の木陰に座ったまま
While still sitting in the summer shade
アイスを口に放り込んで
Tossing an ice cream into my mouth
風を待っていた
Waiting for the wind
はい、ということで、『花に亡霊』でした！AZKi先輩、ようこそ！
Yes, and so, that was "Hana ni Bourei"! AZKi-senpai, welcome!
お邪魔します！
Pardon me for being here!
イエーイ！
Yay!
みんな、こんこんこんこんこんあずき！
Everyone, kon-kon-kon-kon-kon-AZKi!
右手にマイク、左手に地図、あなたのハートをゼロゲッサー！
Microphone in my right hand, map in my left, I'm the Geoguessr for your heart!
ということで、AZKiです！
And so, I'm AZKi!
ようこそです！
Welcome!
わあ、すごい素敵なライブにご招待いただきありがとうございます
Wow, thank you so much for inviting me to such a wonderful live performance.
こちらこそご出演いただきありがとうございます！
The pleasure is mine, thank you so much for performing!
嬉しい！
I'm so happy!
はい、この曲はですね、あの、AZKi先輩にちょっと「歌いたい曲アンケート」みたいの、すごい前にね、アンケートありましたね
Yes, this song, well, it was from a "songs you want to sing" survey I gave to AZKi-senpai a long time ago. We had that survey, didn't we?
ありましたね
We did.
はい、そちらで、こよりと一緒に歌いたい曲だとかに書いてくださっていた楽曲でした
Yes, it was a song you wrote down as one you wanted to sing with Koyori.
やっぱり「夏」って聞いて、この曲は外せないなと思いまして
I thought, when you hear "summer," you just can't leave this song out.
そうですね！
That's true!
しかも、あの、アコースティックにめちゃくちゃ合う！
And it fits the acoustic style so well!
めちゃくちゃ合う！
It fits so well!
まあ、あの、コメント欄でもあったんですけど、あの、これAZKiちのおはこやんみたいな
Well, it was also in the comments, but people were saying, "This is like AZKi-chi's signature song."
えっ、でもこよちゃんも歌ってるの見かけてて、よく歌う、あの、せっかく。
Eh, but I've seen Koyo-chan singing it too, she sings it often. So, yeah,
だから、うん、やっぱこの夏の終わりに歌いたいなと思って選びました
I chose it because I really wanted to sing it at the end of this summer.
ねえ。めっちゃ浄化されました、横で歌ってて
Right. I felt so purified, singing next to you.
えー、こよちゃんどうでしたか？
Aw, Koyo-chan, how was it?
いや、本当に良かったですし。え、どうですか？なんか、おはこだけど、このアコースティックとかで歌ったことってございます？
No, it was truly great. How about you? I mean, it's your signature song, but have you ever sung it acoustically before?
あ、でもあんまりないかも
Ah, but maybe not very often.
おお！いや、しかもね、なんかこよちゃんと一緒に歌うことで、なんかこう、え、あずこよある？あずこよある？
Oh! And also, by singing with Koyo-chan, I saw quite a few comments saying, "Eh, AzuKoyo moment? AzuKoyo moment?"
あずこよあるぞ！というね、コメントをちらほら見かけました
There's an AzuKoyo moment!"
見ました見ました。嬉しい
I saw them, I saw them. I'm happy.
嬉しい。ちょっとね、こよもAZKi先輩の透き通ってる声を、お邪魔しないようにもう頑張って透き通らせました
I'm happy. Koyo also tried her best to sound clear, so as not to get in the way of AZKi-senpai's transparent voice.
みんな床になってくれてるみたいで...
It looks like everyone is becoming the floor...
よかった！よかった！
I'm glad! I'm so glad!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
こよりちゃん、なんと！
Koyo-chan, guess what!
はい！
Yes!
X、トレンド1位！
We're trending #1 on X!
えー！嬉しい！
Whaaa! I'm so happy!
わあ、みんなありがとう！
Wow, thank you everyone!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
もっともっと呟いちゃってください！
Please tweet more and more!
嬉しい！
I'm so happy!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
それではですね、もっと語りたいこともあるんですけども...
Well then, there's more I'd like to talk about, but...
そろそろ次の曲に行きたいと思うので...
I'd like to move on to the next song soon, so...
次のメンバーをまず呼び込みたいと思いますよ！
First, I'll call the next members to the stage!
ミオ先輩とビブー！
Mio-senpai and Biboo!
ミオちゃん、ビブー！いぇーい！
Mio-chan, Biboo! Yay!
お、元気元気！元気あり余ってる！
Oh, full of energy! So much energy!
元気元気！すごーい！
Full of energy! Amazing!
なんかちょっとエモくてしっとり...
It was a bit emotional and mellow...
ね、しっとりしたね！
Yeah, it was mellow!
そうですね、二人でさぁ！
That's right, between the two of you!
あれあれ？袖からだったから！
Oh? We were watching from the wings!
二人は元気してたんですけどね！
But we were full of energy!
えらい！
Good job!
えらい？えらい！
Good job? Good job!
エモい！エモい！
Emotional! Emotional!
エモい、えらい、エモい...
Emo, Erai, Emo...
エモスティック？ん？エモスティック...
Emostick? Hm? Emostick...
エモーショナル！
Emotional!
はい、エモーショナルにお届けしております！
Yes, we are bringing it to you emotionally!
あ、ではですね、ここでちょっとあずき先輩お着替えに...
Oh, right. At this point, AZKi-senpai is going to go change...
お着替えしてきます！一瞬お願いします！
I'm going to change! Please excuse me for a moment!
でもエモーショナルといえばね...
But speaking of emotional...
ロックンロールかと思っていた、カリ先輩とビブーの風と一緒もめちゃよかったですよ！
I thought it was rock 'n' roll, but the performance of Calli-senpai and Biboo was also really good!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
だから、あの、みんな「え、ロックじゃないの？」みたいに...
So, like, everyone was like, "Wait, isn't it rock?"
戸惑ってるのも...
They seemed confused...
ロックじゃないよ、ロックじゃないよ！
It's not rock! It's not rock!
あ、おかえりなさい！早い！お着替え早い！
Oh, welcome back! So fast! You changed so quickly!
はい、というわけで、夏はね、エモい曲が多い感じですが...
Yes, so summer feels like it has many emotional songs...
次からはどうなるのか...
I wonder what's next...
ここからはですね、3曲続けてお届けいたします！
From here, we'll be performing three songs in a row!
次の曲はですね、こちらのあずき先輩、ミオ先輩、ビブーちゃんの3人に歌っていただきますので...
The next song will be sung by AZKi-senpai, Mio-senpai, and Biboo-chan...
はい、頑張るぞ！
Yes, let's do our best!
こよりはしばらくバイバイです！
Koyori will say bye-bye for a while!
お着替え頑張って！頑張るよー！
Good luck with your costume change! We'll do our best!
ここで一発やっぱロックンロール？
Maybe some rock 'n' roll after all?
え、ロックンロール？ええ？
What, rock 'n' roll? Huh?
また台本にないことを...戸惑ってる...ふふふ...
Something else not in the script... I'm confused... hehe...
はい、というわけでね、まあここから3曲続くんですけど...
Yes, so as I said, three songs will follow...
じゃあこの3人で歌わせていただきます！
Well then, the three of us will sing for you!
それでは聴いてください。
Please listen to...
スパークル。
Sparkle.
スパークル [original ver.]
作詞・作曲 野田洋次郎
Sparkle [original ver.]
Lyrics & Composition: Yojiro Noda
まだこの世界は
It seems that this world
僕を飼いならしてたいみたいだ
Still wants to keep me tamed
望み通りだろ
Just as you wished, right?
美しくもがくよ
I will struggle beautifully
互いの砂時計
While gazing at
眺めながらキスをしようよ
Each other's hourglass, let's kiss
さよならから一番遠い
At the place furthest
場所で待ち合わせよう
From "goodbye", let's meet up
ついに時はきた
The time has finally come
昨日までは序章の序章で
Until yesterday it was just the prologue of the prologue
飛ばし読みでいいから
You can just skim through it
ここからが僕だよ
From here on, it's the real me
経験と知識と
With experience, knowledge,
カビの生えかかった勇気を持って
And a courage that had started to gather mold
未だかつてないスピードで
At a speed never seen before
君のもとへダイブを
I'll dive towards where you are
まどろみの中で 生温いコーラに
While dozing off, with a lukewarm cola,
ここではないどこかを夢見たよ
I dreamed of a place other than here
教室の窓の外に
Outside the classroom window,
電車に揺られ運ばれる朝に
In the mornings spent swaying on a train
運命だとか未来だとか
No matter how much words like
って言葉がどれだけ手を
"fate" or "future" try to
伸ばそうと届かない
Reach out, we fall in love
場所で僕ら恋をする
In a place they can't reach
時計の針も二人を
The hands of the clock
横目に見ながら進む
Move on while glancing at us
こんな世界を二人で
Let's live through this world
一生いや何章でも
For a lifetime, no, for as many chapters as it takes
生き抜いてゆこう
Let's live through it together
「初めまして」なんてさ
Words like "Nice to meet you"
遥か彼方へと追いやって
I've chased them far away
千年周期を一日で息しよう
Let's live a thousand-year cycle in a single day
辞書にある言葉で
With words found in a dictionary
出来上がった世界を憎んだ
I hated the world as it was made
万華鏡の中で
Inside a kaleidoscope
８月のある朝
One August morning
君は僕の前で
In front of me, you
ハニかんでは澄ましてみせた
Smiled shyly and played it cool
この世界の教科書のような笑顔で
With a smile like a textbook for this world
嘘みたいな日々を　規格外の意味を
Days like a lie, meanings out of the ordinary
息切らしていいから　望んだよ
I wished for them, even if I ran out of breath
そしたらドアの外に　君が全部抱えて立ってたよ
And then you were standing outside the door, carrying it all
運命だとか未来とかって言葉がどれだけ手を
No matter how much words like fate or future
伸ばそうと届かない場所で
Reach out, in a place they can't touch
僕ら恋をしよう
Let's fall in love
愛し方さえも　君の匂いがした
Even the way I loved smelled of you
歩き方さえも　その笑い声がした
Even the way I walked sounded like your laughter
いつか消えてなくなる　君のすべてを
All of you, that will someday disappear
この眼に焼き付けておくことは　もう権利なんかじゃない　義務だと思うんだ
Burning it into my eyes is no longer just a right, I think it's a duty
運命だとか未来とかって言葉がどれだけ手を
No matter how much words like fate or future
伸ばそうと届かない場所で僕ら恋をする
Reach out, we fall in love in a place they can't touch
時計の針も二人を横目に見ながら進む
The clock hands move while glancing at the two of us
そんな世界を二人で一生　いや、何章でも
In such a world, for a lifetime, no, for however many chapters
生き抜いていこう
Let's live it through together
ガーネット
Garnet
グラウンド駆けてくあなたの背中は
Your back as you ran across the field
空に浮かんだ雲よりも自由で
Was freer than the clouds floating in the sky
ノートに並んだ四角い文字さえ
Even the square characters lined up in my notebook
すべてを照らす光に見えた
Looked like light illuminating everything
ガーネット
Garnet
あー...
Ah...
好きという気持ちが分からなくて
I didn't understand the feeling of "love"
二度とは戻らないこの時間が
This time that will never return
その意味を私に教えてくれた
Taught me the meaning of that
あなたと過ごした日々を
The days I spent with you
この胸に焼き付けよう
I'll sear them into my heart
思い出さなくても
Even if I don't try to remember
大丈夫なように
So that I'll be okay
いつか他の誰かを
Even if someday I
好きになったとしても
Fall in love with someone else
あなたは
You will
ずっと
Always
特別で
Be special
大切で
And precious
またこの季節が
This season
めぐってく
Comes around again
はじめて人を
The day I first
愛したあの日を
Loved someone
皆さん、お待たせしました！
Everyone, sorry to keep you waiting!
ちょっと生ならではという感じで、原因不明の機材トラブルが起きてしまいまして
Being a live broadcast, we had some equipment
trouble of unknown cause
今のところ、あの、原因も分かってないんですけども
As of now, we don't know the cause, but...
Wow!
わお！
Our singing so good it broke the stream!
お待たせしました
Sorry for the wait.
復旧したので、また再開していきたいと思います！
Since it's back up, let's get back to it!
それでは改めて ガーネットから始めさせていただこうと思います
Then, once again, we'd like to start with 'Garnet'.
皆さん お待たせしてごめんね
Everyone, sorry for the wait.
なんか ちょっとビリビリってなったみたいで
It seems there was a bit of a crackle.
耳とかも えー 調子合わせながら このアコースティックライブで
I hope you can fix your ears while listening to this acoustic live performance...
耳直していただければと思います はい
...adjusting them along the way. Yes.
はい！ では ウィングさんもありがとうございます
Yes! And thank you to Wings-san too.
添えていただきありがとうございます
Thank you for accompanying us.
では 行きますか？ はい OK?
Well then, shall we? Yes. OK?
OK! OK!
ガーネット
作詞・作曲：奥 華子
Garnet
Lyrics/Composition: Oku Hanako
グラウンド駆けてく あなたの背中は
Running across the ground, your back...
空に浮かんだ 雲よりも自由で
...is freer than the clouds floating in the sky.
ノートに並んだ 四角い文字さえ
Even the square letters lined up in my notebook...
すべてを照らしだす 光に見えた
...looked like light illuminating everything.
好きという気持ちが 分からなくて
I didn't understand the feeling of 'liking' someone...
二度とは戻れない この時間だ
...and this time will never come back.
その意味を私に 教えてくれた
You taught me the meaning of that.
あなたと過ごした日々を この胸に焼き付けよう
I'll etch the days I spent with you into my heart.
思い出さなくても 大丈夫なように
So that it's okay, even if I don't remember them.
いつか他の誰かを 好きになったとしても
Even if I fall in love with someone else someday...
あなたは ずっと
You will always be...
特別で
...special...
大切で
...precious...
またこの季節が 巡ってくる
...and this season will come around again.
初めて二人で 話した放課後
That after school when we talked for the first time...
誰も知らない 笑顔を探していた
I was looking for a smile that no one knew.
遠くであなたの はしゃいでる声に
Hearing your cheerful voice in the distance...
なぜだか胸が 痛くなったの
Somehow my chest began to ache.
変わってゆくことを 怖がってたの
I was afraid of things changing.
ずっと友達のまま いれる気がした
I felt like we could stay friends forever.
終わってくものなど ないと思っていた
I thought that there was nothing that would end.
果てしない時の中で あなたと出会えたことが
In the endless flow of time, the fact that I met you...
何よりも私を 強くしてくれたね
...strengthened me more than anything else.
移りゆく明日に たどり着いたとしても
Even if I arrive at a shifting tomorrow...
あなたは ずっと
You will always be...
特別で
...special...
大切で
...precious...
またこの季節が やってくる
...and this season will come around again.
いつまでも 忘れないと
That I'll never forget you...
あなたが言ってくれた夏
...the summer you told me so.
時が流れ 今頃私は
Time passes, and about now...
涙が こぼれてきた
...tears have begun to fall.
あなたと過ごした日々を この胸に焼き付けよう
I'll etch the days I spent with you into my heart.
思い出さなくても 大丈夫なように
So that it's okay, even if I don't remember them.
変わらぬもの 好きになったとしても
Even if I've come to love things that don't change
あなたはずっと
You've always been
特別で
special
大切で
and precious
またこの季節が巡ってくる
and this season will come around again
打上花火
Uchiage Hanabi (Fireworks)
作詞・作曲：米津玄師
Lyrics & Composition: Kenshi Yonezu
あの日見渡した渚を
The beach I looked out at that day
今も思い出すんだ
I still remember it now
砂の上に刻んだ言葉
The words carved into the sand
君の後ろ姿
The sight of your back
寄り返す波が 足元をよぎり
The waves that wash back pass by my feet
何かをさらう
and sweep something away
夕凪の中
In the evening calm
日暮れだけが通り過ぎて行く
only the sunset passes by
パッと光って咲いた 花火を見ていた
Watching the fireworks that bloomed with a flash
きっとまだ終わらない夏が
Surely the summer that hasn't ended yet
曖昧な心を 解かして繋いだ
Melted and connected our vague hearts
この夜が続いて欲しかった
I wanted this night to continue
あと何回君と同じ花火を見れるかなって
Wondering how many more times I can see the same fireworks with you
笑う顔に何ができるだろうか
What can I do for your smiling face?
傷つくこと 喜ぶこと 繰り返す波と情動
Being hurt, being happy, the repeating waves and emotions
焦燥 最終列車の音
Impatience, the sound of the last train
何度でも言葉にして君を呼ぶよ
I'll call your name in words over and over
波を選びもう一度
Choosing the waves, once more
もう二度と悲しまずに済むように
So that you'll never have to be sad again
ハッと息を飲めば 消えちゃいそうな光が
If I take a sudden breath, a light that seems it might vanish
きっとまだ胸に住んでいた
was surely still living in my chest
手を伸ばせば触れた あったかい未来は
The warm future I could touch if I reached out
密かに二人を見ていた
was secretly watching the two of us
パッと花火が 夜に咲いた
Fireworks suddenly bloomed in the night
夜に咲いて 静かに消えた
Bloomed in the night and quietly vanished
離さないで もう少しだけ
Don't let go, just a little bit longer
もう少しだけ このままで
Just a little bit longer, stay like this
あの日見渡した渚を
The beach I looked out at that day
今も思い出すんだ
I still remember it now
砂の上に刻んだ言葉
The words carved into the sand
君の後ろ姿
The sight of your back
パッと光って咲いた 花火を見ていた
Watching the fireworks that bloomed with a flash
きっとまだ終わらない夏が
Surely the summer that hasn't ended yet
曖昧な心を 解かして繋いだ
Melted and connected our vague hearts
この夜が続いて欲しかった
I wanted this night to continue
続いて欲しかった
I wanted it to continue
はい！ということで、カリオペちゃんと「打上花火」を歌わせていただきました！
Yes! And so, I sang "Uchiage Hanabi" with Calliope-chan!
花火綺麗でした！
The fireworks were beautiful!
イエーイ！
Yay!
楽しかったー！
That was fun!
どうでしたか？
How was it?
わー、とっても楽しかったよ。
Wow, it was so much fun.
嬉しいー！カリオペちゃんとこうやってね、
I'm so happy! I never thought the day would come...
デュエットできる日が来るとは思わず。もうホントに。
...when I'd get to do a duet with Calliope-chan like this. Truly.
イエーイ、嬉しい。
Yay, I'm happy.
頑張りました、低い声で。
I did my best with the low voice.
もうかっこよかった！
It was so cool!
めっちゃかっこよかった！
So very cool!
ありがとう。
Thank you.
このコントラストがすごい好きだから、
I really like this contrast, so...
そう、低い声でやりたいなと思って。
...I wanted to do it with a low voice.
そう、すごいね、男性パートをね、頑張って歌ってくださいました。
Yeah, you did a great job singing the male part.
カリオペちゃんありがとう！
Thank you, Calliope-chan!
こちらこそありがとうございました。楽しかった。
Thank you as well. It was fun.
楽しかったー！
That was fun!
ということで、ここでね、またメンバーのみんなを...
And so, I'd like to call all the members...
...呼びたいと思います！
...back here!
全員集合！
Everyone assemble!
Come on!
はい！最高だった！
Yes! That was the best!
良かったねー！
That was great!
良かった！
Great!
もうずっと最高です！
It's been the best the whole time!
素敵でした。
It was wonderful.
ありがとうございました。
Thank you very much.
ということでですね、改めまして。
And so, once again.
本日はアコースティックライブ出演いただき、
Thank you very much for performing in...
そして見ていただき、ありがとうございます！
...and watching today's acoustic live!
ありがとうございます！ Thank you so much!
Thank you very much! Thank you so much!
もうホントに、選曲神だったなって自分で思うぐらいね。
Honestly, I think the setlist was just divine.
自画自賛！
Self-praise!
自画自賛です！
I am praising myself!
自画自賛するぐらい皆さんがホントに素晴らしくて、
The performances were so wonderful that I can't help but praise them.
幸せなひとときを過ごさせていただきました。
I had a truly happy time.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you.
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
はい、ということでですね、なんと次が...
Yes, so, believe it or not, the next one...
...最後の曲になってしまいまいた！
...is the last song!
えーーー！！
Ehhh!!
今来たばっかりー！
We just got here!
今来たばっかりだよ。
You just got here.
でもラストはこの全員揃って歌いますので、
But for the finale, we'll all sing together...
お楽しみにしていただけると嬉しいんですが。
...so we hope you look forward to it.
ラストに行く前に、ちょっとせっかくなんで...
Before the finale, since we're here...
...ピアノの前でスクショタイムとか。
...how about a screenshot time in front of the piano?
おおー！
Ohhh!
素敵！
Wonderful!
いい思い出！
A great memory!
思い出思い出。
A memory, a memory.
皆さんも撮ってください。
Everyone, please take pictures too.
あ、じゃあ、じゃあ小夜はしゃがむね。
Ah, then, then Koyori will crouch.
イエーイ！
Yay!
ぷりーず、
Please...
はい、ポーズ。どうですか？
...okay, pose. How is it?
どうですか？
How is it?
ワーイ！
Waii!
イエーイ！
Yay!
いい写真！
What a great photo!
イエーイ！
Yay!
はい、じゃあ戻りますか。
Okay, shall we head back?
ぜひぜひツイートしてくださいね。
Please, please tweet it.
思い出になりますね。
It'll be a memory.
アップして。
Post it.
ハッシュタグよろしく。ありがとうございます。
Use the hashtag, please. Thank you.
ではちょっと最後の曲に行く前に、
Now, before the last song...
一言ずついただこうかなと思いますので。
...I'd like to get a few words from everyone.
ビブーどうだった？
Bijou, how was it?
めっちゃ楽しかったー！
It was so much fun!
みんなすごいですね。
Everyone is amazing.
ビブーもすごかった！
Bijou was amazing too!
あへ、あへ、ありがとうございます。
Hehe, thank you.
“Japanese is very good sugoi”ってコメントいっぱいありました。
There were lots of comments saying “Japanese is very good, amazing”.
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
日本語、もうちょっと難しいです。
Japanese... it's a bit more difficult.
でも頑張りました。
But I did my best.
すごかったよー。
You were amazing.
めっちゃプラクティスしてくれたもんね。
You practiced so much, didn't you?
めっちゃプラクティス！
Much practice!
ホントすごい！
Really amazing!
ナイスジョブ、ビブー。
Nice job, Bijou.
ENのライブ8月にありまして、
There was an EN live in August...
そちらのアーカイブが9月25日とかだったかな。
...and I think the archive is available until September 25th or so.
もうちょっと見れますので、ぜひそちらも見てください。
You can still watch it, so please check that out too.
チェックチェック。
Check, check.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
そしてカリ先輩！
And Calli-senpai!
私、もっと歌いたかった。
I wanted to sing more.
この夜が続いて欲しかった。
I wanted this night to continue.
ほんとよ。
Really.
足りなさそう、あと3倍ぐらいは歌いたそう。
It's not enough; I want to sing about three times more.
3時間いけそう。
I could go for three hours.
ほんとに楽しかった。
It was really fun.
実は私昔、スタートから、
Actually, back in the day, from the start...
3Dがゲットしたとき、
...when I got my 3D...
毎回生ライブやってた。
...I did live concerts every time.
生3Dライブ、そうそうそう、やってたから...
We used to do live 3D concerts like this...
まあ、超久しぶりですね。ずっとまたやりたかったけど、まあ機会がなくて...
It's been quite a while. I've wanted to do this again for ages, but I haven't had the chance.
結構、収録がね、あの、入るようになったりとかしましたからね。
Yeah, we've started doing more pre-recorded content lately.
そうだね。だから本当にありがとうございます。とても楽しかったです。
That's true. So, thank you very much. I had a lot of fun.
可愛かった！めちゃかっこよかった！
That was so cute! You looked so cool!
そして、カリ先輩は今日、Mythの4周年のライブから駆けつけで...
And Calli-senpai came straight here from the Myth 4th Anniversary live today!
そう、アコースティック、4周年。あ、5周年？ああ、4周年。頑張りました。
Yeah, the acoustic live, 4th... wait, 5th? Ah, 4th anniversary. I worked hard.
できねーそんなこと！
I can't do something like that!
あれもチェックしてほしい。ね、そう、是非ですね、こちらアーカイブもあるので。Busy busy, very busyだったけど、楽しいから。
I hope you'll check that out too. Yes, please, there's an archive for it as well. It was busy, busy, very busy, but it was fun.
こちらこそありがとうございました。そして、ミオ先輩！
Thank you as well. And Mio-senpai!
はい！いや、こうやってね、みんなと一緒に歌うっていうことが楽しかったね。
Yes! Gosh, getting to sing together with everyone like this was so much fun.
うん。すごいね。あの、今日、貴重な時間をもらえて、本当に嬉しかったです。ありがとうございました！
Yeah. It was wonderful. I'm really happy I got to spend this precious time with you today. Thank you so much!
いや本当にミオ先輩はソロライブ終わったばかりで。確かに。そっちも大変だったのに...
I mean, Mio-senpai just finished her solo live. Right. Even though she was busy with that...
でも、なんか出たいなーって思ったんだけど、なんかどうなってるか不安だから、ちょっと曲数は少なくしてもらったんだけど...
I really wanted to be here, but I was worried about my stamina, so I asked to have a few less songs...
1曲少ない！それでも！
Just one less song! Even so!
気遣いいただきありがとうございました。
Thank you for being so considerate.
でも出れてよかった。ソロライブも本当に最高だったし、アーカイブありますんで是非皆さん見てください。
But I'm glad I could participate. My solo live was also the best, so there's an archive, please go check it out everyone.
そして、あずき先輩！
And next, AZKi-senpai!
いや本当に今日、いい時間を、最高の時間を過ごさせていただきました。見てくださった方もありがとうございましたっていうのと...
Honestly, I had such a wonderful time, the best time today. I want to thank everyone who watched, and...
今回こよちゃんが主催してくれて、このライブがありますので、こよちゃんありがとう。
This live happened because Koyo-chan organized it, so thank you, Koyo-chan.
ビジューさんも、あの素敵な演奏もありがとうございました。本当に最高でした。素晴らしい。
And Bijou-san, thank you for the wonderful performance too. It was truly the best. Amazing.
いや、またイン・サマーですか？イン・ウィンターあるんですか？
So, this was 'In Summer'... will there be an 'In Winter'?
やりたいなー！っていう気持ちを込めて！
I'd love to! I'm putting that feeling into it!
好評だったら第2回できますので！声次第ですよね！
If it's well-received, we can do a second one! It depends on your feedback!
今日のライブの感想とかを是非是非教えていただけたらなと思います。ありがとうございました！
So please, please let us know what you thought of today's live. Thank you so much!
そして、あずき先輩は11月にソロライブが、はい、ありますので、よかったら是非見に来ていただけたら嬉しいです。
And AZKi-senpai has a solo live in November, so please come and see her if you can!
めちゃくちゃ楽しみにしております！
I'm looking forward to it so much!
配信チケットもありますんでね、是非よろしくお願いします。
Streaming tickets are also available, so please check them out.
ということでですね、今日この主催をしてみて、みんなの歌聞きてぇ、みんなと一緒に歌いてぇ、みたいな気持ちもすごくありまして...
So, having organized this today, I really felt like I wanted to hear everyone sing and sing together with everyone...
そしてピアノと一緒に歌いたいっていう気持ちもすごくありまして。本当に最高の時間でした。ありがとうございました！
And I also really wanted to sing along with the piano. It was truly the best time. Thank you so much!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
最後の曲、ちょっと名残惜しいんですけど、はい、このまま歌わせていただきたいと思います。皆さん、何の曲だと思いますか？
It's a bit sad that it's the last song, but we're going to sing it now. What song do you guys think it is?
What song do you think we're going to sing last, chat? Do we see your guesses?
What song do you think we're going to sing last, chat? Let's see your guesses!
Last song, last song... What do you think? Any guesses?
青春アーカイブ。あ、それは最初に流れてたから。
'Seishun Archive'... ah, that was playing at the start.
あ、正解もありそうですね！ありそうありそう！
Oh, looks like some people might have the right answer! I see them!
結構割れてますね。夏休みの歌といえば、この曲で締めさせていただきたいと思います！
The guesses are quite divided. Speaking of summer vacation songs, we'd like to close with this one!
それでは、聞いてください。secret base ～君がくれたもの～
Please listen: secret base ~Kimi ga Kureta Mono~
君と夏の終わり 将来の夢 大きな希望 忘れない
The end of summer with you, dreams for the future, and big hopes—I won't forget them
10年後の8月 また出会えるのを信じて
Believing that we'll meet again in August, ten years from now
最高の 思い出を...
Bringing back the best of memories...
出会いはふとした瞬間 帰り道の交差点で 声をかけてくれたね 「一緒に帰ろう」
Our meeting was so sudden, at the intersection on the way home, you called out to me: 'Let's go home together'
僕は照れくさそうに カバンで顔を隠しながら...
Embarrassed, I hid my face behind my bag...
笑顔見せながら
While showing a smile,
本当はとってもとっても 嬉しかったよ
the truth is I was very, very happy.
あぁ 花火が夜空 きれいに咲いて ちょっとセツナク
Ah, the fireworks bloom beautifully in the night sky, a little bittersweet.
あぁ 風が時間とともに 流れる
Ah, the wind flows along with time.
嬉しくて 楽しくて 冒険もいろいろしたね
We were happy and having fun, we went on many adventures together.
二人の秘密の基地の中
Inside our secret base.
君と夏の終わり 将来の夢 大きな希望 忘れない
I won't forget the end of summer with you, our dreams for the future, or our great hopes.
10年後の8月 また出会えるのを信じて
Believing that we'll meet again in August, ten years from now.
君が最後まで心から 「ありがとう」叫んでいたこと 知っていたよ
I knew that you were shouting "Thank you" from the bottom of your heart until the very end.
涙をこらえて 笑顔でさよなら セツナイよね
Holding back tears, saying goodbye with a smile, it's bittersweet, isn't it?
最高の思い出を...
The best memories...
あぁ 夏休みもあと少しで 終わっちゃうから
Ah, because summer vacation will be over in just a little while.
あぁ 太陽と月 仲良くして
Ah, let the sun and the moon get along.
悲しくて 寂しくて 喧嘩もいろいろしたね
We were sad and lonely, we had many fights too.
二人の秘密の基地の中
Inside our secret base.
君が最後まで心から 「ありがとう」叫んでいたこと 知っていたよ
I knew that you were shouting "Thank you" from the bottom of your heart until the very end.
涙をこらえて 笑顔でさよなら セツナイよね
Holding back tears, saying goodbye with a smile, it's bittersweet, isn't it?
最高の思い出を...
The best memories...
突然の...
Due to a sudden...
...転校で...
...school transfer...
...どうしようもなく
...there was nothing I could do.
手紙書くよ 電話もするよ 忘れないでね 僕のことを
I'll write letters, I'll call you too, so please don't forget about me.
いつまでも 二人の基地の中
Forever, inside our base.
君と夏の終わり ずっと話して 夕日を見てから星を眺め
The end of summer with you, we talked forever, watched the sunset, then gazed at the stars.
君の頬を流れた涙は ずっと忘れない
I will never forget the tears that flowed down your cheeks.
君が最後まで大きく手を振ってくれたこと きっと忘れない
I'm sure I won't forget how you waved your hand so hard until the very end.
だからこうして 夢の中で ずっと永遠に...
And so, like this, in my dreams, forever and ever...
君と夏の終わり 将来の夢 大きな希望 忘れない
I won't forget the end of summer with you, our dreams for the future, or our great hopes.
10年後の8月 また出会えるのを信じて
Believing that we'll meet again in August, ten years from now.
君が最後まで心から 「ありがとう」叫んでいたこと 知っていたよ
I knew that you were shouting "Thank you" from the bottom of your heart until the very end.
涙をこらえて 笑顔でさよなら セツナイよね
Holding back tears, saying goodbye with a smile, it's bittersweet, isn't it?
最高の思い出を...
The best memories...
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
Thanks everyone!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
バイバイ！
Bye-bye!
See you someday!
バイバイ！
Bye-bye!
Peace.
完全生3D Acoustic Live in Summer
Fully Live 3D Acoustic Live in Summer